A Guide to the Smithey & Boynton, Architects & Engineers Records, 1922-1985
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
- Series II: Project Files and Drawings, 1923-1985
  - #836 - Watson High School addition (Covington, VA), 1948-1950 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - #837 - First Presbyterian Church alterations and additions, 1949-1963 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - #838 - Richardson Wayland Electrical Corporation (Roanoke, VA), 1948 (Box 19, Folder 26, Box 50)
  - #839 - Harrisonburg High School, 1950-1964 (Box 19, Folder 27-29, Box 20, Folder 1-2, Box 50)
  - #840 - Pollard Jr., Roy service station (Roanoke, VA), 1949 (Box 20, Folder 3, Box 50)
  - #841 - Norfolk and Western Railway passenger station alterations (Farmville, VA), 1948-1949 (Box 20, Folder 4-5, Box 50)
  - #842 - Eckman, Hensel residence (Pulaski, VA), 1949 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - #843 - Virginia Polytechnic Institute - Danville Extension, 1949-1959 (Box 20, Folder 7-8, Box 50)
  - #844 - Galax High School shop addition, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - #845 - Wytheville High School shop building, 1949 (Box 20, Folder 10, Box 50)
  - #845A - Wytheville High School (Wythe County, VA), 1948-1975 (Box 20, Folder 11-12)
  - #846 - Christ Episcopal Church alterations and additions (Roanoke, VA), 1952-1956 (Box 20, Folder 13-15, Box 50, Box 51)
  - #847 - Mrs. W.R. Staples residence - heating investigation (Roanoke, VA), 1948-1949 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - #848 - Boys' Home cottage #1 (Covington, VA), 1949-1963 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - #849 - Raleigh Court Methodist Church (Roanoke, VA), 1949-1951 (Box 20, Folder 18, Box 51)
  - #850 - Conehurst Elementary School (Roanoke County, VA), 1932-1957 (Box 20, Folder 19, Box 51)
  - #851 - General Electric storage warehouse (Roanoke, VA), 1949-1951 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - #852 - First Federal Building and Loan Association alterations (Roanoke, VA), 1949 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - #853 - Leggett's Department Store Alterations (consulting), 1949 (Box 20, Folder 22, Box 51)
  - #854 - American Theatre Building alterations, 1951-1952 (Box 20, Folder 23, Box 51)
  - #855 - Southwest Virginia Savings and Loan Association (Roanoke, VA), 1949-1956 (Box 20, Folder 24-25, Box 51)
  - #856 - Cinder Block Incorporated (Roanoke, VA), 1949 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - #857 - Staunton Elementary School,, 1949-1956 (Box 20, Folder 27, Box 51)
  - #857B - Robert E. Lee High School (Staunton, VA), 1949-1958 (Box 21, Folder 1-10)
  - #858 - Bland County Correctional Farm (White Gate, VA), 1949-1958 (Box 21, Folder 11-15, Box 22, Folder 1-2, Box 52)
  - #859 - William A. Dickinson residence, 1949-1950 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - #860 - VPI President's House (Blacksburg, VA), 1950-1956 (Box 22, Folder 4-6, Box 52)
  - #861 - B. Forman and Sons - store alterations (Roanoke, VA), 1949-1951 (Box 22, Folder 7, Box 52)
  - #862 - Wood Service Station (Lewisburg, VA), 1949-1951 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - #863 - Jackson, Wiley N. residence (Roanoke, VA), 1949-1950 (Box 22, Folder 9, Box 52)
  - #864 - Waynesboro Schools - boiler conversion, 1949-1951 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - #865 - Hollins College - main building toilet alterations,, 1949 (Box 22, Folder 11, Box 52)
  - #866 - St. Johns Episcopal Church (Glasgow, VA), 1949 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - #867 - Virginia Bridge Company (Roanoke, VA), 1949 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - #868 - Andrew Lewis High School - shop addition (Salem, VA), 1949-1950 (Box 22, Folder 13, Box 52)
  - #869 - Canada Dry Bottling Company (Roanoke, VA), 1949 (Box 22, Folder 14, Box 52)
  - #870 - Montgomery County Schools - heating changes, 1949-1952 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - #871 - Goldsmith, John residence (Radford, VA), 1949-1950 (Box 22, Folder 16, Box 52)
  - #872 - Blackwell residence (Roanoke, VA), 1949 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - #873 - Franklin Moore residence (Roanoke, VA), 1949 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - #874 - Morgan-Eubank Furniture Company alterations, 1950-1953 (Box 22, Folder 19, Box 52)
  - #875 - Virginia Polytechnic Institute - Processing Laboratory (Blacksburg, VA), 1949-1968 (Box 22, Folder 20-25, Box 52)
  - #875 - VPI - Processing Laboratory (Blacksburg, VA), 1950-1956 (Box 23, Folder 1-4, Box 52)
  - #876 - Dublin Elementary School (Pulaski County, VA), 1950-1955 (Box 23, Folder 5, Box 53)
  - #878 - Boy's Home preliminaries (Covington, VA), 1949-1957 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - #881 - Andrew Lewis High School arcade enclosure, 1949-1950 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - #882 - Cinder Block Incorporated - 1950 jobs, c. 1950 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - #883 - Service Station #2 for Roy Pollard, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - #884A - Christiansburg Institute - excavation and foundation, 1951 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - #884B - Christiansburg Institute - superstructure for new buildings, 1951-1958 (Box 23, Folder 11-12, Box 53)
  - #884D - Christiansburg Institute - outside utilities, 1951-1955 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - #885 - Hunter, W.P. residence (Roanoke, VA), 1950 (Box 23, Folder 14, Box 53)
  - #887 - Castlewood High School - shop addition, 1949-1951 (Box 23, Folder 15, Box 53)
  - #888 - Franklin County Training School, 1950-1953 (Box 23, Folder 16-17, Box 53)
  - #889 - Salvation Army - transient shelter building (Roanoke, VA), 1950 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - #890 - Colonial American Bank - Williamson Road Branch, 1950-1953 (Box 23, Folder 19, Box 53)
  - #891 - H.B. Boynton residence alterations, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 20, Box 53)
  - #894 - Rocky Mount High School gymnasium addition (Franklin County, VA), 1950-1963 (Box 23, Folder 21-22, Box 53)
  - #895 - Jewell Valley School (Buchanan County, VA), 1950 (Box 23, Folder 23, Box 53)
  - #896 - Wytheville Elementary School, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - #897 - Ironto Elementary School (Montgomery County, VA), 1952-1954 (Box 23, Folder 25-26, Box 53)
  - #898 - Bookshelves for Judge D.A. Kuyk, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - #899 - Combined High and Elementary Negro Schools (Manassas, VA), 1950-1951 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - #900 - Boys' Home Cottage #2 (Covington, VA), 1950-1952 (Box 24, Folder 1, Box 53)
  - #900A - Boys' Home #1 and #2 (Covington, VA), 1951 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - #901 - Rocky Mount High School addition (Franklin County, VA), 1950-1957 (Box 24, Folder 3-5, Box 53)
  - #902 - Building for Roy Pollard (Roanoke, VA), 1950 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - #903 - Department of Motor Vehicles branch office (Roanoke, VA), 1950-1952 (Box 24, Folder 7-8, Box 53)
  - #904 - Belspring Elementary School (Pulaski County, VA), 1950-1951 (Box 24, Folder 9, Box 53)
  - #905 and #905A - Pulaski National Bank alterations, 1950-1959 (Box 24, Folder 21, Box 53)
  - #908 - Northwood Elementary School (Pulaski County, VA), 1950-1951 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - #908A - Northwood Elementary School - multipurpose room (Pulaski County, VA), 1953-1958 (Box 24, Folder 11-12, Box 53)
  - #909 - Calfee Training School (Pulaski County, VA), 1950-1951 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - #910 - Riverlawn Elementary School (Pulaski County, VA), 1950-1955 (Box 24, Folder 14-15, Box 53)
  - #910A - Riverlawn Elementary School (Pulaski County, VA), 1951-1958 (Box 24, Folder 16-17, Box 54)
  - #911 - Swartz, W.P. residence,, 1950-1951 (Box 24, Folder 18, Box 54)
  - #912 - Oakland Elementary School (Carroll County, VA), 1950-1961 (Box 24, Folder 19-20, Box 25, Folder 1, Box 54)
  - #913 - Augusta County Schools - consulting, 1950-1956 (Box 25, Folder 2, Box 54)
  - #914 - Twin County Motor Company store building (Galax, VA), 1950 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - #917 - Raven Elementary School (Tazewell County, VA), 1953-1956 (Box 25, Folder 4-5, Box 54)
  - #918 - Bandy Elementary School (Tazewell County, VA), 1950-1951 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - #919 - Cliffield Elementary School (Tazewell County, VA), 1950-1952 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - #920 - Maxie Elementary School (Buchanan County, VA), 1950 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - #922 - Double Envelope Corporation (Roanoke, VA), 1950-1951 (Box 25, Folder 9, Box 54)
  - #923 - Presbyterian Church (Martinsville, VA), 1950 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - #924 - Equipment Service Company (Roanoke, VA), 1950-1951 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - #925 - Pine Creek Elementary School (Russell County, VA), 1952-1956 (Box 25, Folder 12-13, Box 54)
  - #926 - Copper Creek Elementary School (Russell County, VA), 1952-1958 (Box 25, Folder 14-15, Box 54)
  - #927 - Masonic Temple alterations (Roanoke, VA) (Box 25, Folder 16, Box 54)
  - #928 - Newbern Elementary School (Pulaski County, VA), 1951-1954 (Box 25, Folder 17-18, Box 54)
  - #928A - Newbern Elementary School (Pulaski County, VA), 1953-1954 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - #929 - Snowville Elementary School (Pulaski County, VA), 1951-1953 (Box 25, Folder 20-21)
  - #929A - Snowville Elementary School (Pulaski County, VA), 1953-1954 (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - #930 - VPI Poultry Plant (Blacksburg, VA), 1950-1955 (Box 25, Folder 23-27, Box 54)
  - #931 - Sword's Creek Elementary School (Russell County, VA), 1951-1958 (Box 26, Folder 1-2, Box 54)
  - #932 - Lightweight Aggregate Corporation (Roanoke, VA), 1950 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - #933 - Woodlawn Consolidated School (Carroll County, VA), 1950-1954 (Box 26, Folder 4, Box 54)
  - #934 - Hiwassee Elementary School (Pulaski County, VA), 1951-1953 (Box 26, Folder 5-6, Box 54)
  - #934A - Hiwassee Elementary School addition (Pulaski County, VA), 1953-1955 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - #935 - First National Bank (Clifton Forge, VA), 1952-1955 (Box 26, Folder 8, Box 55)
  - #936 - First National Exchange Bank (Roanoke, VA), 1950-1953 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - #937 - Watson School (Alleghany County, VA), 1950-1959 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - #938 - Cinder Block Incorporated - new batching plant, 1951 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - #939 - Bland Correctional Farm - lime plant (White Gate, VA), 1950-1951 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - #940 - Noland Company Incorporated (Arlington, VA), 1950-1951 (Box 26, Folder 13, Box 55)
  - #941 - A.A. Campbell - consultation service, 1950-1951 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - #942 - First Presbyterian Church - choir loft alterations (Roanoke, VA) (Box 26, Folder 15, Box 55)
  - #943 - Christiansburg Elementary School (Montgomery County, VA), 1951-1963 (Box 26, Folder 16-17, Box 55)
  - #944 - Draper Elementary School (Pulaski County, VA), 1951-1955 (Box 26, Folder 18-19)
  - #945 - Boys' Home Cottage #3 (Covington, VA), 1951-1952 (Box 26, Folder 20-21, Box 55)
  - #946 - William Gresham Elementary School (Pulaski County, VA), 1951-1954 (Box 26, Folder 22-23, Box 55)
  - #947 - Vicker Elementary School (Montgomery County, VA), 1951-1953 (Box 26, Folder 24-25, Box 55)
  - #948 - Christiansburg High School and addition (Montgomery County, VA), 1952-1958 (Box 26, Folder 26, Box 27, Folder 1-3, Box 55)
  - #949 - Shawsville High School (Montgomery County, VA), 1951-1952 (Box 27, Folder 4, Box 55)
  - #950 - Cambria School addition (Montgomery County, VA), 1951 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - #951 - Auburn High School (Montgomery County, VA), 1951-1954 (Box 27, Folder 6-7, Box 55)
  - #952 - Pre-Shrunk Masonry Sales Corporation (Roanoke, VA), 1951-1953 (Box 27, Folder 8, Box 55)
  - #953 - Tazewell High School, 1952-1954 (Box 27, Folder 9-12, Box 56)
  - #954 - Tannersville Junior High School (Tazewell County, VA), 1951-1953 (Box 27, Folder 13, Box 56)
  - #955 - Col. Richard Lee residence (Rocky Mount, VA), 1951-1952 (Box 27, Folder 14, Box 56)
  - #956 - West Virginia Pulp and Paper Company (Covington, VA), 1951-1967 (Box 27, Folder 15-19, Box 28, Folder 1-6, Box 56)
  - #957 - H.H. Bailey Museum (Goshen, VA), 1951-1953 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - #958 - South Roanoke Methodist Church, 1952-1959 (Box 28, Folder 8-13, Box 57)
  - #959 - First and National Merchants Bank alterations (Radford, VA), 1953-1954 (Box 28, Folder 14, Box 57)
  - #961 - N & W Overall Company (Rocky Mount, VA), 1951 (Box 28, Folder 15, Box 57)
  - #962 - Rowe Furniture Company (Salem, VA), 1951 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - #963 - Double Envelope Corporation (Roanoke, VA), 1951 (Box 28, Folder 17, Box 57)
  - #964 - H.A. Prilliman residence (Roanoke, VA), 1952-1953 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - #965 - St. James Episcopal Church (Roanoke, VA), 1952-1957 (Box 28, Folder 19, Box 57)
  - #966 - Rocky Mount High School (Franklin County, VA), 1950-1953 (Box 28, Folder 20-21, Box 57)
  - #967 - Norfolk and Western Shop and Storage Building (Lambert's Point, VA), 1951-1953 (Box 29, Folder 1-4, Box 57)
  - #968 - Warrenton High School (Fauquier County, VA), 1951-1960 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - #969 - Double Envelope Corporation, 1950-1951 (Box 29, Folder 6, Box 58)
  - #970 - Valley High School (Bath County, VA), 1952-1954 (Box 29, Folder 7-8, Box 58)
  - #970A - Valley High School (Bath County, VA), 1953-1975 (Box 29, Folder 9-18)
  - #970A - Valley High School (Bath County, VA), 1953-1955 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - #970B - Valley High School - sewer and sewage treatment (Bath County, VA), 1955-1956 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - #971 - Winchester Children's Home (Winchester, VA), 1951-1961 (Box 30, Folder 3, Box 58)
  - #972 - Cambria School Bus Shop (Cambria, VA), 1951-1952 (Box 30, Folder 4, Box 58)
  - #973 - Dublin High School shop building (Pulaski County, VA), 1953-1955 (Box 30, Folder 5, Box 58)
  - #974 - Claremont Elementary School (Pulaski County, VA), 1952-1957 (Box 30, Folder 6-7, Box 58)
  - #975 - Hillsville High School (Carroll County, VA), 1953-1955 (Box 30, Folder 8-11, Box 58)
  - #976 - VPI Office and Laboratory Building (Holland, VA), 1952 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - #977 - American Legion Auditorium alterations (Roanoke, VA), 1951-1954 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - #978 - Admiral Carlton Wright residence, 1951-1952 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - #979 - Raleigh Court Presbyterian Church (Roanoke, VA), 1951-1959 (Box 30, Folder 15-18, Box 31, Folder 1-3, Box 59)
  - #980 - Franklin County Courthouse (Rocky Mount, VA), 1953-1969 (Box 31, Folder 4-6, Box 59)
  - #980B - Franklin County Courthouse (Rocky Mount, VA), 1954-1955 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - #981 - Roanoke Terminal Incorporated Bus Stations, 1952-1954 (Box 31, Folder 8-9)
  - #982 - Christiansburg Negro Elementary School (Montgomery County, VA), 1952-1954 (Box 31, Folder 10-11, Box 59)
  - #983 - John Puhl Products Company (Salem, VA), 1949-1955 (Box 31, Folder 12-16, Box 59)
  - #984 - Boys' Home - small boys' cottages (Covington, VA), 1952-1958 (Box 32, Folder 1-2, Box 59, Box 60)
  - #985 - Bank of Shawsville,, 1952-1959 (Box 32, Folder 3, Box 60)
  - #986A - Keister Elementary School (Harrisonburg, VA), 1953 (Box 32, Folder 4, Box 60)
  - #986B - Waterman Elementary School (Harrisonburg, VA), 1954 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - #986A - Keister School and #986B - Waterman School (Harrisonburg, VA), 1952-1964 (Box 32, Folder 6-7)
  - #987 - First National Exchange Bank - Raleigh Court Branch (Roanoke, VA), 1952-1953 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - #988 - Dante Colored School (Russell County, VA), 1953-1958 (Box 32, Folder 9-10)
  - #989 - Buford, Paul C. residence (Roanoke, VA), 1952-1953 (Box 32, Folder 11, Box 60)
  - #990 - Winchester Health Center,, 1951-1952 (Box 32, Folder 12, Box 60)
  - #991 - VPI - Livestock and Poultry Disease Laboratory (Blacksburg, VA), 1952-1958 (Box 32, Folder 13-19, Box 60)
  - #991A - VPI Livestock and Poultry Disease Research Laboratory Annex (Blacksburg, VA), 1955-1956 (Box 32, Folder 20, Box 33, Folder 1-2, Box 60)
  - #992 - Radford Community Hospital (Radford, VA), 1942-1964 (Box 33, Folder 3-5, Box 60)
  - #992B - Radford Community Hospital (Radford, VA), 1953 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - #993 - National Bank of Blacksburg alterations (Blacksburg, VA), 1952-1953 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - #994 - Shawsville Primary School (Montgomery County, VA), 1953-1965 (Box 33, Folder 8-9, Box 60)
  - #995 - Hidden Valley Country Club - swimming pavillion (Roanoke, VA), 1952-1955 (Box 33, Folder 10, Box 60)
  - #995A - Hidden Valley Country Club - locker house (Roanoke, VA), 1953-1957 (Box 33, Folder 11, Box 60)
  - #996 - Franklin County Training School addition, 1952 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - #997 - Blacksburg Negro Elementary School (Montgomery County, VA), 1952-1954 (Box 33, Folder 13, Box 60)
  - #998 - Hillsville Elementary School (Carroll County, VA), 1952-1964 (Box 33, Folder 14-17, Box 60)
  - #999 - Mr. M.B. Smith - private bridge, 1952 (Box 33, Folder 18, Box 60)
  - #1114 - Additions to J. H. Oakies Mortuary (Box 61)
  - #1185 - Goode Elementary School (Bedford County, VA), 1958 (Box 33, Folder 19, Box 61)
  - [#1208?] - VPI - Biochemistry, Microbiology, and Nutrition Laboratory, Blacksburg, VA, drawing, 1959 (Box-folder Oversize box, Folder Folder 5)
  - #1261 - Thaxton Elementary School (Bedford County, VA), 1959-1960 (Box 33, Folder 20, Box 61)
  - #1284 - VPI Agronomy Department Service Building (Blacksburg, VA), 1961 (Box 34, Folder 1, Box 61)
  - #1311 - VPI Dairy Barns (Blacksburg, VA), 1961 (Box 34, Folder 2, Box 61)
  - #1312 - Fauquier County High School (Warrenton, VA), 1962 (Box 34, Folder 3-4, Box 61)
  - #1398 - Roanoke Civic Center, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 5, Box 61)
  - #1401 - J.M. Oakey's Funeral Home, 1964-1965 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - #1420 - Montvale School addition (Bedford County, VA), 1963 (Box 34, Folder 7, Box 61)
  - #1429M - Hollins College, Miss Burton's House - porch addition, photographs (Hollins, VA), 1967 (Box 34, Folder 7a)
  - #1459 - VPI Home Economic Center (Blacksburg, VA), 1966-1967 (Box 34, Folder 8-9, Box 61)
  - #1508 - VPI Plant Pathology Head House and Greenhouse, 1966 (Box 34, Folder 10, Box 62)
  - #1559 - East Farquier Elementary School (Box 62)
  - #1560 - Warrington Elementary School (Box 62)
  - #1564 - William Byrd High School (Roanoke, VA), 1967-1969 (Box 34, Folder 11-13, Box 62)
  - #1578 - North Farquier Elementary School (Box 62)
  - #1579 - South Farquier Elementary School (Box 62)
  - #1582 - J.M. Oakey Inc. Funeral Home (Vinton, VA), 1970 (Box 34, Folder 14, Box 62)
  - #1625 - Wythe County Community Hospital, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 15, Box 63)
  - #1625A - Wythe County Community Hospital, 1971-1972 (Box 34, Folder 16-18, Box 63)
  - #1625B - Wythe County Community Hospital, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 19-20, Box 63)
  - #1647 - Marshall Junior High School (Fauquier County, VA), 1973-1974 (Box 34, Folder 21-22, Box 35, Folder 1-4, Box 63)
  - #1667 - Cedar Lee Junior High School, 1973-1975 (Box 35, Folder 5-10, Box 64)
  - #1718 - Fauquier County Vocational - Technical School, 1973-1974 (Box 35, Folder 21-23, Box 64)
  - #1971 - J.M. Oakey Inc. Funeral Home - North Chapel, 1974 (Box 35, Folder 14-15, Box 64)
  - #2273 - Staunton River High School (Bedford County, VA), 1978 (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - #2568 - Montvale Elementary School (Bedford County, VA), 1981 (Box 35, Folder 17, Box 64)
  - #2635 - Williamson Road Parking Garage (Roanoke, VA), 1982 (Box 35, Folder 18-19)
  - #2681 - Jefferson Forest School (Bedford County, VA), 1982-1985 (Box 36, Folder 1, Box 64)
  - Unnumbered drawing, Hotel for Covington, Virginia, by E.R. Gilbert and Louis Phillippe Smithey, Architect & Engineer, 1928 (Box-folder Oversize box, Folder Folder 2)
    Louis Philippe Smithey, Architect & Engineer, Roanoke & Covington; not framed; VTF 3118
    Gilbert, E.R., creator Smithey, Louis Philippe, 1890-1966
  - Topographical maps and unnumbered site plans (Box 65)
- Series III: Other Architects - Johnson Associates International, February 1968
  Series III contains blueprints and building specifications for structures designed or consulted on by firms other than Smithey & Boynton.
  - Johnson Associates International - Farmland Dairies Inc. processing plant (Wallington, NJ), February 1968 (Box-folder 36-2 to 36-4)